HEBER BERMUDEZ

Statistician - Colombian

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Statistician with a special focus on applied statistics and epidemiological data analysis, I have experience collecting, analyzing, interpreting, and presenting quantitative information, providing insight and recommendations on policies and strategies. I have worked in data visualization for business intelligence, written reports, development and implementation of predictive models, database management and software development. I possess strong IT and analytical skills, as well as the interpersonal and communication skills to share findings with colleagues and clients. I apply statistical theories and methods to solve practical problems in a range of sectors, including; health, engineering, education, the environment, software companies, among others. I love music, chess, data science, arificial intelligence, and science popularization.

EDUCATION

National University of Colombia.

2015-2021, Medellín, Colombia.

Undergraduate in Statistics.

GPA: 4.1/5.0

SENA. 2013-2014, Ibagué, Colombia.

Technologist in industrial production managemen.

SENA. 2010-2011, Ibagué, Colombia.

Technician in analysis, design and software development.

EXPERIENCE

International cultural exchange.

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021, Custer, SD, United States.

• Participated in a cultural exchange program as a student to strengthen English skills and learn about American culture. Worked in customer support.

Infection and Cancer Research Group.

Dec 2020 - Jul 2021, Medellín, Colombia.

Internship as Epidemiological data analyst, Antioquia University.

- Supported statistical analyzes of epidemiological and biomedical data for research projects.
- Research collaborator, creation of written reports of findings.

Unalytics, Research incubator.

Jan 2019 - Jun 2020, Medellín, Colombia.

Assistant student, National University of Colombia.

- Founded and managed a research incubator where lead a group of 15 people, the group was attached to the school of statistics as a pedagogical strategy.
- Taught theoretical and practical skills in the area of applied statistics, data science, machine learning and artificial intelligence.
- Coordinated academic products for participation in contests, congresses and colloquiums. See more: https://unalyticsteam.github.io/unalytics/

Biosuplies SAS.

Jan 2014 - Feb 2015, Ibagué, Colombia.

SENA Intern, Biosuplies SAS

- Created forms and process manuals as well as software programs to automate administrative tasks such as stock management and quality control.
- Developed software that allows fast, easy and effective prescription of masterly medicines, which was distributed among the main Hospitals allied with the company in municipalities of Colombia.
- Participated in the laboratory certification visit that was carried out by the National Institute for Food and Drug Surveillance.

AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

Student Representative.

2019

Student representative of the Conflict Resolution and Disciplinary Aspects Committee of the Faculty of Sciences of the National University of Colombia, dedemocratically elected by vote.

Best degree project.

2011

Technical College, Best degree project related to software programming.

ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

XIII National statistics colloquium

2021

Attendant, National University of Colombia.

XII National statistics colloquium

2019

 $Speaker, Web\ application,\ Machine\ Learning\ for\ text\ analysis,$

National University of Colombia.

XXIX International statistical symposium

2019

Speaker, Text mining to study some terminologies

about data science in Colombia, Northern University.

Dataton BC

2019

Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank.

Modeling of credit risk from the digital trace, top 20% Kaggle Challenge.

Dataton BC

2018

Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank.

Text mining to identify expenses by categories.

CERTIFICATIONS, MOOCS

Artificial Intelligence for medicine.

2022

Coursera, Deeplearning.ai

AWS S3 Basics.

2022

Course ra

SQL for Data science.

2021

Coursera, DAVIS University

Structuring Machine Learning Projects.

2020

Coursera, Deeplearning.ai

Neural Networks and Deep Learning.

Coursera, Deeplearning.ai

Tableau Public for Project Management. 2020

2020

Coursera

Introduction to data science. 2020

Coursera, Autonomous University of Mexico

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

R, Python, Java, Visual Basic, React Native. **Programming**

Databases SQL.

Version control tools Git, GitHub.

Data Visualization, BI Power BI, Tableau.

Machine Learning, Artificial Intelligence Pandas, Scikit-learn, Tidyverse, Tensorflow, Pytorch.

GCP, AWS, AZURE. Cloud computing

Typesetting Document Latex.

LANGUAGES

English Intermediate.

Spanish Native.